RAVINDRA BAKKAMANTHALA

 $\textbf{Portfolio}: \underline{\text{https://ravindrabakkamanthala.github.io/}} \hspace{0.1cm} | \hspace{0.1cm} \underline{\text{LinkedIn:}} \hspace{0.1cm} \underline{\text{https://bit.ly/34J1iX8}}} \hspace{0.1cm} | \hspace{0.1cm} \underline{\text{Email:}} \\ \text{ravindrab240@gmail.com} \\$

About Me:

My Name is Ravindra Bakkamanthala, I am a Full Stack developer with 5+ years of experience in Software Industry. I am a Constant Learner, Dedicated team player, Smart Coder, Innovative thinker and I love to take up challenging tasks and provide the best Output for my Customers.

Technical Skills:

- Java (Expert), Python (Intermediate), C (Basics)
- MySQL, Maria DB, Postgres, MongoDB (NoSQL)
- AWS (EC2, S3, Dynamo DB, Route 53)
- Junit, Mockito

- JavaScript, Angular JS, Angular, React, D3, CSS, HTML
- Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Struts, Vaadin
- Kafka, XACML, Elastic Search, Drools, AEM, Jenkins
- GIT, SVN

Other Skills:

• Multitasking, Team Player, Excellent ability in leading the team, Good Adaptability and Excellent Presentation skills.

Education:

Degree	Board	Year	CGPA	
Master's in Computer Engineering	University of Houston Clearlake	2014	3.4	
B. Tech in Electrical and Electronics Engineering	JNTU-K, India	2012	7.4/10(CGPA)	

Employment:

ATT Labs | Software Engineer | Middletown, NJ | April 2019 - Present

- Developed Log Parser streaming application which monitors the ansible logs and shows the live logs on GUI.
- Developed Workflow Process Engine to execute the workflow tasks using Spring Boot Micro Service application.
- Developed Network Topology to Show the Network Configuration in Visualization form using D3 js.
- Developed Non-Open Stack Action implementations (Start/Stop/Restart/Configure) the VNF's on fly Asynchronously.

Verizon | Software Engineer | Piscataway, NJ | Dec 2018 - Mar 2019

- Migrated the Verizon My Business Portal Shopping Cart and Checkout Components (End to End) from Angular JS to Angular 7 and Monolithic to Microservices.
- Lead the Offshore team and closely monitored the work on day to day basis.

ATT Labs | Software Engineer | Middletown, NJ | Feb 2015 - Dec 2018

- Developed the AT&T ECOMP Policy Engine from Scratch (Based on Research team POC).
- Developed the application using Vaadin Framework (GUI) and backend with Java Servlets and Python Modules.
- Migrated the complete application from Vaadin to Angular JS and Servlets to Microservices and used Hibernate for Dao Layer.
- Developed the Dynamic rendering Form Templates in GUI based on YML models.
- Open Sourced the application in 2016 as ONAP (Open Network Automation Platform).

Cynosure Technologies LLC | Intern | Houston, TX | Dec 2014 – Feb 2015

- Developed Online Quiz tool portal for new hires assessment.
- Worked on fixing the issues related to portal in the guidance of Senior developers.

Personal and Free-Lancing Projects:

GitHub: https://github.com/ravindrabakkamanthala/

WebCrawler: The Application crawls the webpages and store the metadata to database for search optimization.

- Developed the web application with React Js to monitor and feed the urls from GUI.
- Developed the Crawler and Service with Spring Boot and both interacts with Mongo db and Redis.
- Service App will act as Queue on serving the URLs to crawler, and it monitors the urls which are already visited using Redis.
- Crawler App will fetch the metadata and add the href to Queue and stores the meta data to database.

Portfolio Website: https://ravindrabakkamanthala.github.io/

• My Portfolio Application is developed using Angular 8, Bootstrap, Angular Material.

Softworld Technologies: http://www.softworldtechnologies.com/

- Designed and developed the Softworld Technologies company website from scratch.
- Developed the Frontend application using Angular 9.
- Developed the Backend Microservices using Spring Boot for managing the Jobs/Employees/Recruiters services.
- Developed the Email Notification System (Job Subscriptions/New Job Notifications/ Signup)
- Deployed the Application in AWS EC2.
- Used MySQL for storing the metadata related to website services.